[
    {
        "local_id": "2de74614ec78d252584d3e97fcb4bb7b",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement",
        "description": "Encyclopedia article about the civil rights movement in the American South, one of the most significant and successful social movements in the modern world. Black Georgians formed part of this southern movement for full civil rights and the wider national struggle for racial equality. From Atlanta to the most rural counties in Georgia's southwest Cotton Belt, black activists protested white supremacy in a myriad of ways--from legal challenges and mass demonstrations to strikes and self-defense. In many ways, the results were remarkable. As late as World War II (1941-45) black Georgians were effectively denied the vote, segregated in most areas of daily life, and subject to persistent discrimination and often violence. But by 1965, sweeping federal civil rights legislation prohibited segregation and discrimination, and this new phase of race relations was first officially welcomed into Georgia by Governor Jimmy Carter in 1971. The Civil Rights Digital Library received support from a National Leadership Grant for Libraries awarded to the University of Georgia by the Institute of Museum and Library Services for the aggregation and enhancement of partner metadata. GSE identifier: SS2H1",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 291,
                "end": 298,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "atlanta",
                "ner_confidence": 0.968999981880188,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 329,
                "end": 336,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "georgia",
                "ner_confidence": 0.975600004196167,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 898,
                "end": 905,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "georgia",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9758999943733215,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 918,
                "end": 930,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "jimmy carter",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9775999784469604,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 944,
                "end": 972,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "civil rights digital library",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9894999861717224,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 1052,
                "end": 1073,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "university of georgia",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9865999817848206,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 1081,
                "end": 1121,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "institute of museum and library services",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9891999959945679,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 1179,
                "end": 1182,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "gse",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9294999837875366,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "7fd85c0ad29ddc407ee6884621fcc910",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement",
        "description": "Central High, Little Rock, AR \"Negro Johnny Gray, 15, smashes his fist against the face of a white student during a scuffle on 14th St. 1958.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 0,
                "end": 12,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "central high",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9514999985694885,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 14,
                "end": 25,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "little rock",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9351000189781189,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 27,
                "end": 29,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "ar",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9036999940872192,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 37,
                "end": 48,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "johnny gray",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9848999977111816,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "9819335365ed196643f01b8044816a73",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement",
        "description": "Daugharty, Janice. \"Civil Rights Movement,\" n.d. Series 2: The Short Stories (Unpublished), 2, Box: 5; Box: 6; Box: 7. Janice Daugharty Papers, MS-22. Valdosta State University Archives and Special Collections. Box 7, Folder 26.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 0,
                "end": 17,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "daugharty, janice",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9641000032424927,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 119,
                "end": 135,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "janice daugharty",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9839000105857849,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 151,
                "end": 209,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "valdosta state university archives and special collections",
                "ner_confidence": 0.984499990940094,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "1681232f11898bf57e05124a0a2c7d65",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement",
        "description": "Selma, AL \"As youthful negores applaud, young white girl holds aloft burning Conferderate battle flag which they set afire in street outside Brown's Chapel AME Church, 1965.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 0,
                "end": 5,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "selma",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9329000115394592,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 7,
                "end": 9,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "al",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9491999745368958,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 141,
                "end": 166,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "brown's chapel ame church",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9764000177383423,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "3a3fe19794114282b93e904d6231ead4",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil rights movement",
        "description": "Archival soundbites of civil rights activists Martin Luther King Jr., Stokely Carmichael, H. Rap Brown, Malcolm X. Interviews with Robert Moses and Alvin Poussaint, who say we should not celebrate MLK alone, but remember the whole history of the civil rights movement. Sammy Davis Jr., Leonard Bernstein, James Baldwin, Harry Belafonte participating in march.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 46,
                "end": 67,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "martin luther king jr",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9915000200271606,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 70,
                "end": 88,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "stokely carmichael",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9921000003814697,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 90,
                "end": 102,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "h. rap brown",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9887999892234802,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 104,
                "end": 113,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "malcolm x",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9914000034332275,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 131,
                "end": 143,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "robert moses",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9905999898910522,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 148,
                "end": 163,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "alvin poussaint",
                "ner_confidence": 0.992900013923645,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 197,
                "end": 200,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "mlk",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9897000193595886,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 269,
                "end": 283,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "sammy davis jr",
                "ner_confidence": 0.991100013256073,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 286,
                "end": 303,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "leonard bernstein",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9911999702453613,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 305,
                "end": 318,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "james baldwin",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9909999966621399,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 320,
                "end": 335,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "harry belafonte",
                "ner_confidence": 0.991599977016449,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "42a5f3e8247c998f524f99af31e3d9a5",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement exhibit",
        "description": "Lincoln University students browse an exhibit that reads \"You can kill the dreamer, but you can't kill the dream\".",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 0,
                "end": 18,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "lincoln university",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9830999970436096,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "0e8f9d9970b57624e37dec1ec24eb500",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement exhibit",
        "description": "Lincoln University students browse an exhibit that reads William Loren Katz's quote \"If you believe a man has no history worth mentioning, it is easy to assume that he has no humanity worth defending\".",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 0,
                "end": 18,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "lincoln university",
                "ner_confidence": 0.98089998960495,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 57,
                "end": 77,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "william loren katz's",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9878000020980835,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "f60146fe1c04c364e449474664cef1a9",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement and Unemployment",
        "description": "William Bradley briefly speaks about the exploitation and discrimination of black labor from slavery to present. He also discussed how protests and demonstrations - violent and non-violent - can be a vehicle for change. Prior to Williams Bradley's lecture, California State University, Sacramento Professor Leonard D. Cain speaks about fair housing in Sacramento.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 0,
                "end": 15,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "william bradley",
                "ner_confidence": 0.991100013256073,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 229,
                "end": 247,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "williams bradley's",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9829999804496765,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 257,
                "end": 296,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "california state university, sacramento",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9772999882698059,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 307,
                "end": 322,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "leonard d. cain",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9897000193595886,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 352,
                "end": 362,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "sacramento",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9616000056266785,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "eef10cc959d276184cd7d8db05b936ee",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Albany Civil Rights Movement Museum",
        "description": "The Albany Civil Rights Movement Museum opened in the Old Mt. Zion Baptist Church in Albany in 1998. The first mass meeting of the Albany Movement was held at the church in 1961, and in the 1990s the church building was converted into the museum. Known today as the Albany Civil Rights Institute, the museum moved to a new facility next to the church in 2008. Photograph of the Freedom Singers in front of the Old Mt. Zion Baptist Church, the location of the Albany Civil Rights Movement Museum in Albany, Georgia. It is a brick church with two low spires rising from the front. The former church was renovated in the 1990s, and the museum opened in 1998. The first mass meeting of the Albany Movement was held at the church in 1961. The Albany Movement was the first mass movement in the modern civil rights era to have as its goal the desegregation of an entire community, and it resulted in the jailing of more than 1,000 African Americans in Albany and surrounding rural counties.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 4,
                "end": 39,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "albany civil rights movement museum",
                "ner_confidence": 0.902899980545044,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 85,
                "end": 91,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "albany",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9649999737739563,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 266,
                "end": 295,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "albany civil rights institute",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9786999821662903,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 459,
                "end": 494,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "albany civil rights movement museum",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9035000205039978,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 498,
                "end": 504,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "albany",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9703999757766724,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 506,
                "end": 513,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "georgia",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9692000150680542,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 946,
                "end": 952,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "albany",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9620000123977661,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "48b7f76a76c9b4831957a366000b5461",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement: Community History",
        "description": "A celebration of the Civil Rights Movement and the Greensboro Sit-Ins. This work consists of interviews with William A. Thomas Jr., Dr. Elizabeth Laizner, Willa B. Player, and Clarence C. Malone that offer insight into organization and protest activities in the African-American communities.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 51,
                "end": 69,
                "label": "EVENT",
                "entity_span": "greensboro sit-ins",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9020000100135803,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 109,
                "end": 129,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "william a. thomas jr",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9904999732971191,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 136,
                "end": 153,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "elizabeth laizner",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9919000267982483,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 155,
                "end": 170,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "willa b. player",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9900000095367432,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 176,
                "end": 194,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "clarence c. malone",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9911999702453613,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "88e09b3582055c7d191e385e76204a47",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Albany Civil Rights Movement Museum",
        "description": "Encyclopedia article about the Albany Civil Rights Movement Museum, which commemorates the 1960s civil rights movement in southwest Georgia. The museum is housed in the old Mt. Zion Baptist Church where mass meetings were held, including the first mass meeting of the Albany Movement in November, 1961. The Civil Rights Digital Library received support from a National Leadership Grant for Libraries awarded to the University of Georgia by the Institute of Museum and Library Services for the aggregation and enhancement of partner metadata.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 31,
                "end": 66,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "albany civil rights movement museum",
                "ner_confidence": 0.955299973487854,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 132,
                "end": 139,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "georgia",
                "ner_confidence": 0.977400004863739,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 173,
                "end": 196,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "mt. zion baptist church",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9326000213623047,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 307,
                "end": 335,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "civil rights digital library",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9907000064849854,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 415,
                "end": 436,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "university of georgia",
                "ner_confidence": 0.989300012588501,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 444,
                "end": 484,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "institute of museum and library services",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9896000027656555,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "35879e90335649d0d7f73efc00be46c9",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Albany Civil Rights Movement Museum",
        "description": "The Albany Civil Rights Movement Museum (later the Albany Civil Rights Institute) opened in 1998 in the former Old Mt. Zion Church. In 1961 Martin Luther King Jr. organized a mass meeting of civil rights activists, which met at the church. The museum moved to a new facility adjacent to Old Mt. Zion in 2008. Photograph of the Albany Civil Rights Museum in Albany, Georgia. The Albany Civil Rights Movement Museum is located in the Old Mt. Zion Baptist Church. It is a brick church with two low spires rising from the front. The former church was renovated in the 1990s, and the museum opened in 1998. The first mass meeting of the Albany Movement was held at the church in 1961. The Albany Movement was the first mass movement in the modern civil rights era to have as its goal the desegregation of an entire community, and it resulted in the jailing of more than 1,000 African Americans in Albany and surrounding rural counties.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 4,
                "end": 39,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "albany civil rights movement museum",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9749000072479248,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 51,
                "end": 80,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "albany civil rights institute",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9865999817848206,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 140,
                "end": 162,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "martin luther king jr",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9760000109672546,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 327,
                "end": 353,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "albany civil rights museum",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9688000082969666,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 357,
                "end": 363,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "albany",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9728000164031982,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 365,
                "end": 372,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "georgia",
                "ner_confidence": 0.968999981880188,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 378,
                "end": 413,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "albany civil rights movement museum",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9646000266075134,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 892,
                "end": 898,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "albany",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9646000266075134,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "67d2ef637571aa7b435e155dcee60d87",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement Oral History Project",
        "description": "Civil Rights Oral History Project: Implementing the Foxfire Learning Concept in Greene County, Alabama, submitted for consideration to the Racial Justice Priority Team Board of Homeland Ministries, written by the Institutional Development and Economic Affairs Service.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 0,
                "end": 33,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "civil rights oral history project",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9837999939918518,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 80,
                "end": 93,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "greene county",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9404000043869019,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 95,
                "end": 102,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9553999900817871,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 139,
                "end": 173,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "racial justice priority team board",
                "ner_confidence": 0.987500011920929,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 177,
                "end": 196,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "homeland ministries",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9857000112533569,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 213,
                "end": 267,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "institutional development and economic affairs service",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9904999732971191,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "fd079e1818a0624f02352be063678bd9",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Modern Civil Rights Movement in Alabama",
        "description": "Encyclopedia article about the modern civil rights movement in Alabama which began with a single act of civil disobedience by Rosa Parks in Montgomery in 1955. It began to fade from the public eye a decade later, following the formation of the original Black Panther Party in Lowndes County. During the intervening years, Alabama was the site of some of the most defining events of the civil rights era. These events transformed the state and profoundly changed America. The Civil Rights Digital Library received support from a National Leadership Grant for Libraries awarded to the University of Georgia by the Institute of Museum and Library Services for the aggregation and enhancement of partner metadata.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 63,
                "end": 70,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9753999710083008,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 126,
                "end": 136,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "rosa parks",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9785000085830688,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 140,
                "end": 150,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "montgomery",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9715999960899353,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 253,
                "end": 272,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "black panther party",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9803000092506409,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 276,
                "end": 290,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "lowndes county",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9528999924659729,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 322,
                "end": 329,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9763000011444092,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 462,
                "end": 469,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "america",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9717000126838684,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 475,
                "end": 503,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "civil rights digital library",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9905999898910522,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 583,
                "end": 604,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "university of georgia",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9891999959945679,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 612,
                "end": 652,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "institute of museum and library services",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9890999794006348,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "bbcab73cb2689c36e336e92464dd6142",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Catholicism and the Civil Rights Movement",
        "description": "Encyclopedia article about the Catholic Church's involvement with the civil rights movement in Alabama. Most of Alabama's white Catholics shared white southerners' racism and initially opposed the goals of the movement. They preferred order and stability instead of activism for integration and racial justice. Catholic teaching clearly opposed racial discrimination, however, and after the mid-1960s there was little sympathy for segregation. For most of the civil rights movement, the Catholic Church in Alabama remained on the margins of the debates over integration and focused on internal Church affairs. It took the 1965 Selma to Montgomery march for voting rights to draw the Church from the margins into the mainstream of the movement. The Civil Rights Digital Library received support from a National Leadership Grant for Libraries awarded to the University of Georgia by the Institute of Museum and Library Services for the aggregation and enhancement of partner metadata.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 31,
                "end": 46,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "catholic church",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9549999833106995,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 95,
                "end": 102,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9772999882698059,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 112,
                "end": 119,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.977400004863739,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 487,
                "end": 502,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "catholic church",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9280999898910522,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 506,
                "end": 513,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.977400004863739,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 627,
                "end": 652,
                "label": "EVENT",
                "entity_span": "selma to montgomery march",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9139999747276306,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 748,
                "end": 776,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "civil rights digital library",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9904999732971191,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 856,
                "end": 877,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "university of georgia",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9887999892234802,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 885,
                "end": 925,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "institute of museum and library services",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9908999800682068,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "d24a29164b4817c796cdbdd0fecff9c1",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Women of the Civil Rights Movement",
        "description": "This is a research-based project in which students will use primary sources to complete an assignment on Alabama women involved in the Civil Rights movement.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 105,
                "end": 112,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9786999821662903,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "88730f78b35e006aba428ec1c51b47bf",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "America's Civil Rights Movement 1953 - Present",
        "description": "Oral history interview with the Reverend Dr. Bryant George by St. Andrew's Episcopal School student Tom Taylor. In this interview the Rev. Dr. George gives his perspective on the Civil Rights Movement.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 45,
                "end": 58,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "bryant george",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9883000254631042,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 62,
                "end": 91,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "st. andrew's episcopal school",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9873999953269958,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 100,
                "end": 110,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "tom taylor",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9873999953269958,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 143,
                "end": 149,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "george",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9805999994277954,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "1cb8ac9b9ff9f003550c002ae99288e2",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Multi-Organizations in the Civil Rights Movement",
        "description": "Wilfred Ussery, representative of the Congress of Racial Equality (CORE), spoke about civil rights in 1964.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 0,
                "end": 14,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "wilfred ussery",
                "ner_confidence": 0.991599977016449,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 38,
                "end": 65,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "congress of racial equality",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9901000261306763,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 67,
                "end": 71,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "core",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9796000123023987,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "4fe2f4d625ca77dad06ee7697021ab9a",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement in the Black Hills",
        "description": "Presented at the 14th Annual West River History Conference held in Rapid City, South Dakota, October 12-14, 2006. Published in 2006 conference proceedings, pages 360-375.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 67,
                "end": 77,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "rapid city",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9573000073432922,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 79,
                "end": 91,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "south dakota",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9460999965667725,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "98f8ab7b5c59901798c97eb2c6ab501f",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Clergy leading Civil Rights Movement in churches",
        "description": "Four Rockland County clergymen look at a document. Written on the back is \"Nyack Clergy (?) leading Civil Rights movement in churches.\" Seated: Reverend Petty McKinney, St. Philips AME Zion Church, Nyack; Reverend Wilbur Daniels, Nauraushaun Presbyterian Church. Standing: Monsignor James Cox, Rockland State Hospital Chaplain, Orangeburg, and Reverend George Regas, Grace Episcopal Church, Nyack. There's a picture of President John F. Kennedy on the wall behind them.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 5,
                "end": 20,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "rockland county",
                "ner_confidence": 0.955299973487854,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 153,
                "end": 167,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "petty mckinney",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9904000163078308,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 169,
                "end": 196,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "st. philips ame zion church",
                "ner_confidence": 0.979200005531311,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 198,
                "end": 203,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "nyack",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9340000152587891,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 214,
                "end": 228,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "wilbur daniels",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9889000058174133,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 230,
                "end": 261,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "nauraushaun presbyterian church",
                "ner_confidence": 0.983299970626831,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 283,
                "end": 292,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "james cox",
                "ner_confidence": 0.989300012588501,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 294,
                "end": 317,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "rockland state hospital",
                "ner_confidence": 0.984499990940094,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 328,
                "end": 338,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "orangeburg",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9264000058174133,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 353,
                "end": 365,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "george regas",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9886000156402588,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 367,
                "end": 389,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "grace episcopal church",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9815999865531921,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 391,
                "end": 396,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "nyack",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9307000041007996,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 429,
                "end": 444,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "john f. kennedy",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9872000217437744,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "ea86cb880308a5491e88f9a22bd4b7e0",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Gallery of Greats : The Civil Rights Movement",
        "description": "A pamphlet created by the Miller Brewing Company featuring painted portraits (by Clarence Laudric Shivers) and biographies of some of the prominent figures in the Civil Rights movement.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 26,
                "end": 48,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "miller brewing company",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9531999826431274,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 81,
                "end": 105,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "clarence laudric shivers",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9904999732971191,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "9c6df4c2bd78b3580121fd118bfc0a69",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Tuskegee Airmen and the Civil Rights Movement",
        "description": "Digital art created by Edward W. Morast of Ohio Memorial Chapter of the Tuskegee Airmen Inc. about the Tuskegee Airmen and they role they played in Civil Rights Movement in the United States.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 23,
                "end": 39,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "edward w. morast",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9921000003814697,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 43,
                "end": 64,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "ohio memorial chapter",
                "ner_confidence": 0.984000027179718,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 72,
                "end": 92,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "tuskegee airmen inc",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9562000036239624,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 177,
                "end": 190,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "united states",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9214000105857849,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "bae6b440bfc43521434f838f2b676b8c",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Fight for Freedom : The Civil Rights Movement",
        "description": "Oral history interview with Gela O. Portee by St. Andrew's Episcopal School student Christina Splaine. In this interview Ms. Portee presents the Civil Rights Movement from the perspective of a black woman who was a participant.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 28,
                "end": 42,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "gela o. portee",
                "ner_confidence": 0.991599977016449,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 46,
                "end": 75,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "st. andrew's episcopal school",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9876999855041504,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 84,
                "end": 101,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "christina splaine",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9904999732971191,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 125,
                "end": 131,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "portee",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9894000291824341,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "d726f8eebb3b312eaac88d2c7bffc403",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Martin Luther King Jr. during Civil Rights Movement",
        "description": "King's interest in nonviolence became a central tenet of his leadership of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference and helped lead a young generation of African Americans to promote desegregation through peaceful sit-ins. Photograph of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. walking down a street with two unidentified men. He wears a long dark coat and tie and looks left. King, a Baptist minister and president of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference (SCLC), was the most prominent African American leader in the civil rights movement of the 1950s and 1960s.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 0,
                "end": 4,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "king",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9559000134468079,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 79,
                "end": 119,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "southern christian leadership conference",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9894999861717224,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 245,
                "end": 268,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "martin luther king, jr",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9732999801635742,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 368,
                "end": 372,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "king",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9549999833106995,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 414,
                "end": 454,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "southern christian leadership conference",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9876000285148621,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 456,
                "end": 460,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "sclc",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9815000295639038,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "52f6fcbc998c0af7a5f16fefb68008a1",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement scrapbooks. Alabama events volume 8",
        "description": "Topics covered: Federal examiners controversy; Anniston murder trial; Attorney General Nicholas Katzenbach speaks at Mobile; voter registration; Prattville moratorium; Wallace will defy school desegregation guides; new civil rights plan sent to Congress; United States Steel statement. These scrapbooks, compiled by librarians at the Birmingham Public Library, contain newspaper clippings relating to the Civil Rights Movement. The clippings are arranged in three subject areas: national civil rights events, Alabama events, and Mississippi events. The clippings are arranged chronologically within the subject areas.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 47,
                "end": 55,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "anniston",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9229000210762024,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 87,
                "end": 106,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "nicholas katzenbach",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9883999824523926,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 117,
                "end": 123,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "mobile",
                "ner_confidence": 0.968500018119812,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 145,
                "end": 155,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "prattville",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9387999773025513,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 168,
                "end": 175,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "wallace",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9667999744415283,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 245,
                "end": 253,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "congress",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9431999921798706,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 255,
                "end": 274,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "united states steel",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9882000088691711,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 334,
                "end": 359,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "birmingham public library",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9897000193595886,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 509,
                "end": 516,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9794999957084656,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 529,
                "end": 540,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "mississippi",
                "ner_confidence": 0.978600025177002,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "f90565b33c1515e2975579c87cc42993",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement scrapbooks. Mississippi events volume 1",
        "description": "Topics covered: segregation \"watchdog\" committee; Parker lynching; \"Freedom Riders\"; Philadelphia black church burned; voting registration disputes; James H. Meredith; contempt of court charges sought against University of Mississippi officials; Governor Ross Barnett bars Meredith from \"Ole Miss\". These scrapbooks, compiled by librarians at the Birmingham Public Library, contain newspaper clippings relating to the Civil Rights Movement. The clippings are arranged in three subject areas: national civil rights events, Alabama events, and Mississippi events. The clippings are arranged chronologically within the subject areas.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 50,
                "end": 56,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "parker",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9592000246047974,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 85,
                "end": 97,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "philadelphia",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9767000079154968,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 149,
                "end": 166,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "james h. meredith",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9894000291824341,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 209,
                "end": 234,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "university of mississippi",
                "ner_confidence": 0.982699990272522,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 255,
                "end": 267,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "ross barnett",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9850000143051147,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 273,
                "end": 281,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "meredith",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9865999817848206,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 288,
                "end": 296,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "ole miss",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9836000204086304,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 347,
                "end": 372,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "birmingham public library",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9872000217437744,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 522,
                "end": 529,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9789000153541565,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 542,
                "end": 553,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "mississippi",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9790999889373779,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "2d75833fe8cdcdd4bbb572ea8356fcf5",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement scrapbooks. National events volume 3",
        "description": "Topics covered: jury trials voted into rights bill; civil rights bill approved; Georgia defies federal integration policy; Little Rock, Arkansas asks halt to integration; W. Wilson White to head Civil Rights Commission; Virginia and Arkansas to defy integration. These scrapbooks, compiled by librarians at the Birmingham Public Library, contain newspaper clippings relating to the Civil Rights Movement. The clippings are arranged in three subject areas: national civil rights events, Alabama events, and Mississippi events. The clippings are arranged chronologically within the subject areas.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 80,
                "end": 87,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "georgia",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9710000157356262,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 123,
                "end": 134,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "little rock",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9379000067710876,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 136,
                "end": 144,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "arkansas",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9664999842643738,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 171,
                "end": 186,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "w. wilson white",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9818999767303467,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 195,
                "end": 218,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "civil rights commission",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9876999855041504,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 220,
                "end": 228,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "virginia",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9746999740600586,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 233,
                "end": 241,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "arkansas",
                "ner_confidence": 0.968500018119812,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 311,
                "end": 336,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "birmingham public library",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9886999726295471,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 486,
                "end": 493,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9779000282287598,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 506,
                "end": 517,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "mississippi",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9757999777793884,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "725274022bc7f2567551f0743d53ceef",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement scrapbooks. National events volume 11",
        "description": "Topics covered: creation of Adult Education Program; new civil rights proposal; threats of national violence; Atlanta, Georgia violence; Grenada, Mississippi violence. These scrapbooks, compiled by librarians at the Birmingham Public Library, contain newspaper clippings relating to the Civil Rights Movement. The clippings are arranged in three subject areas: national civil rights events, Alabama events, and Mississippi events. The clippings are arranged chronologically within the subject areas.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 28,
                "end": 51,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "adult education program",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9890000224113464,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 110,
                "end": 117,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "atlanta",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9775000214576721,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 119,
                "end": 126,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "georgia",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9746000170707703,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 137,
                "end": 144,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "grenada",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9416999816894531,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 146,
                "end": 157,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "mississippi",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9643999934196472,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 216,
                "end": 241,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "birmingham public library",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9865999817848206,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 391,
                "end": 398,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9797999858856201,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 411,
                "end": 422,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "mississippi",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9787999987602234,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "73f4a5c33bef4419228193e5d61231a7",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement scrapbooks. Alabama events volume 1",
        "description": "Topics covered: Civil rights violations; bus segregation ordered halted by Interstate Commerce Commission; Montgomery bus boycott; attempts at school desegregation; Supreme Court rules bus segregation is unconstitutional; buses fired upon in Montgomery and Birmingham; Birmingham demonstrations; Montgomery bombings. These scrapbooks, compiled by librarians at the Birmingham Public Library, contain newspaper clippings relating to the Civil Rights Movement. The clippings are arranged in three subject areas: national civil rights events, Alabama events, and Mississippi events. The clippings are arranged chronologically within the subject areas.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 75,
                "end": 105,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "interstate commerce commission",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9853000044822693,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 107,
                "end": 117,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "montgomery",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9690999984741211,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 165,
                "end": 178,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "supreme court",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9843000173568726,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 242,
                "end": 252,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "montgomery",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9746999740600586,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 257,
                "end": 267,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "birmingham",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9751999974250793,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 269,
                "end": 279,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "birmingham",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9776999950408936,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 296,
                "end": 306,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "montgomery",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9767000079154968,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 365,
                "end": 390,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "birmingham public library",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9879000186920166,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 540,
                "end": 547,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.982200026512146,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 560,
                "end": 571,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "mississippi",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9825999736785889,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "19af54fdcfc4f7a09e442e16e5bd76af",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement scrapbooks. Alabama events volume 7",
        "description": "Topics covered: mob violence at Marion; Wallace bans nighttime racial demonstrations in Dallas and Perry Counties; civil rights compliance forms signed by several state officials; violence in Montgomery; voter registration; Wallace requests U. S. Marshals; bombs are discovered in Birmingham. These scrapbooks, compiled by librarians at the Birmingham Public Library, contain newspaper clippings relating to the Civil Rights Movement. The clippings are arranged in three subject areas: national civil rights events, Alabama events, and Mississippi events. The clippings are arranged chronologically within the subject areas.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 32,
                "end": 38,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "marion",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9724000096321106,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 40,
                "end": 47,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "wallace",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9458000063896179,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 88,
                "end": 94,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "dallas",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9757000207901001,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 192,
                "end": 202,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "montgomery",
                "ner_confidence": 0.970300018787384,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 224,
                "end": 231,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "wallace",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9480999708175659,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 281,
                "end": 291,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "birmingham",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9721999764442444,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 341,
                "end": 366,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "birmingham public library",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9882000088691711,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 516,
                "end": 523,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9787999987602234,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 536,
                "end": 547,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "mississippi",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9775000214576721,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "f8f20050723fd126862e7909fcdfb9ee",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement scrapbooks. Mississippi events volume 3",
        "description": "Topics covered: Memphis to Jackson march; Philadelphia slayings reopened by Justice Department; eighteen charged with slayings; seven found guilty. These scrapbooks, compiled by librarians at the Birmingham Public Library, contain newspaper clippings relating to the Civil Rights Movement. The clippings are arranged in three subject areas: national civil rights events, Alabama events, and Mississippi events. The clippings are arranged chronologically within the subject areas.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 16,
                "end": 40,
                "label": "EVENT",
                "entity_span": "memphis to jackson march",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9007999897003174,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 42,
                "end": 54,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "philadelphia",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9763000011444092,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 76,
                "end": 94,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "justice department",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9871000051498413,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 196,
                "end": 221,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "birmingham public library",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9873999953269958,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 371,
                "end": 378,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9836000204086304,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 391,
                "end": 402,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "mississippi",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9833999872207642,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "03bf8aed3eab4b41052f94892dd02a6f",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "South Carolina Voices of the Civil Rights Movement",
        "description": "Charleston Museum exhibit publication entitled, \"South Carolina Voices of the Civil Rights Movement: A Conference on the History of the Civil Rights Movement in South Carolina, 1940-1970,\" on the occasion of the opening of an exhibit entitled, \"We'll Never Turn Back,\" a Smithsonian Institution traveling exhibit.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 0,
                "end": 17,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "charleston museum",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9865999817848206,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 161,
                "end": 175,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "south carolina",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9348999857902527,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 271,
                "end": 294,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "smithsonian institution",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9879999756813049,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "901504d54103d1c8875a9d40f4df7fae",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "\"The Early Days of The Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "description": "Bernice Robinson's handwritten notecards for a speech entitled, \"The Early Days of The Civil Rights Movement.\"",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 0,
                "end": 18,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "bernice robinson's",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9686999917030334,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "0aab4c149c0c1045afde15e4a1043566",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "[Program: Black Music and the Civil Rights Movement]",
        "description": "Program for the 1995 Black Music and the Civil Rights Movement which was hosted by the Junior Black Academy of Arts and Letters on February 4, 1995 at the Orpheum Theatre. [10] p. : ill. ; 22 cm.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 87,
                "end": 127,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "junior black academy of arts and letters",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9860000014305115,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "b43875ead1051416a46c0063ab6f379c",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "[Program: Black Music and the Civil Rights Movement]",
        "description": "Program for the Black Music and Civil Rights Movement Concert held on January 20, 1985. The program lists the performers and provides details about the production teams. 1 pamphlet ; 22 x 28 cm., folded to 22 x 14 cm.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 16,
                "end": 61,
                "label": "EVENT",
                "entity_span": "black music and civil rights movement concert",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9243999719619751,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "5c535f92e98e2729887533feac8bcf49",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "[Program: Black Music and the Civil Rights Movement]",
        "description": "Program for the musical tribute sponsored by the Junior Black Academy of Arts and Letters to honor African American music and the civil rights movement, especially in regards to the late Reverend Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.. The event took place on January 18, 1986 at the Music Hall in Fair Park, Dallas. 1 pamphlet ; 22 x 28 cm., folded to 22 x 14 cm.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 49,
                "end": 89,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "junior black academy of arts and letters",
                "ner_confidence": 0.989300012588501,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 200,
                "end": 222,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "martin luther king, jr",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9757000207901001,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 287,
                "end": 296,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "fair park",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9550999999046326,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 298,
                "end": 304,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "dallas",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9498000144958496,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "349c4c850e6d966902f89111e67f4150",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "[Man giving lecture on the civil rights movement]",
        "description": "Photograph of an unidentified man giving a lecture on the civil rights movement at LeTourneau University in Longview, Texas. Taken on April 17th, 2013. 1 photograph : digital, col.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 83,
                "end": 104,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "letourneau university",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9817000031471252,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 108,
                "end": 116,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "longview",
                "ner_confidence": 0.95169997215271,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 118,
                "end": 123,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "texas",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9638000130653381,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "c396e7ff13569742eda62b95cafce0c6",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "An Oral History of the Civil Rights Movement",
        "description": "Oral history interview with Mr. Roy Toodle by St. Andrew's Episcopal School student Neville C. Barbour II about Mr. Toodle's involvement in the Civil Rights Movement.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 32,
                "end": 42,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "roy toodle",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9912999868392944,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 46,
                "end": 75,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "st. andrew's episcopal school",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9861999750137329,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 84,
                "end": 105,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "neville c. barbour ii",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9900000095367432,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 116,
                "end": 122,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "toodle",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9865999817848206,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "6509725f863c9fd0adf51991cbbc396c",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Picket line durring the civil rights movement, 1964",
        "description": "Informational picket line outside Ted Gibson Real Estate (328 Miller Avenue) during the civil rights movement of the 1964.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 34,
                "end": 56,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "ted gibson real estate",
                "ner_confidence": 0.98580002784729,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "fcd12d76a5db08c5eef9aa2c133bed63",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "\"Child of the Civil Rights Movement\" Graphic Organizer",
        "description": "Read the story \"Child of the Civil Rights Movement\" by Paula Young Shelton and Raul Colon in small groups. Discuss the five Ws (who, what, where, when, why) as you read the story with the students. After reading the story, students will reread the text and complete the attached graphic organizer independently.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 55,
                "end": 74,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "paula young shelton",
                "ner_confidence": 0.991599977016449,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 79,
                "end": 89,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "raul colon",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9907000064849854,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "e710dd606f4cf4588be7ed8e98bb5083",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Focus 580; The Civil Rights Movement, 1964-1990",
        "description": "With Julian Bond (Host of America's Black Forum and Narrator of The PBS Series Eyes on the Prize II)",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 5,
                "end": 16,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "julian bond",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9853000044822693,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 68,
                "end": 71,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "pbs",
                "ner_confidence": 0.906499981880188,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "aa52238b067a927a423ffc2e2be48ee7",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement scrapbooks. National events volume 6",
        "description": "Topics covered: Freedom Riders assailed by MacDonald Gallion; U. S. Marshals ordered into Alabama; Freedom Riders linked to Communist Cuba; Civil Rights Commission extended for two year period; ICC orders interstate bus, terminal integration. These scrapbooks, compiled by librarians at the Birmingham Public Library, contain newspaper clippings relating to the Civil Rights Movement. The clippings are arranged in three subject areas: national civil rights events, Alabama events, and Mississippi events. The clippings are arranged chronologically within the subject areas.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 43,
                "end": 60,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "macdonald gallion",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9868000149726868,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 90,
                "end": 97,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9819999933242798,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 134,
                "end": 138,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "cuba",
                "ner_confidence": 0.961899995803833,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 140,
                "end": 163,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "civil rights commission",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9886000156402588,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 194,
                "end": 197,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "icc",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9779000282287598,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 291,
                "end": 316,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "birmingham public library",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9894000291824341,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 466,
                "end": 473,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9836000204086304,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 486,
                "end": 497,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "mississippi",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9833999872207642,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "79d907d1b3946e99ce5d9806c54711c8",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement scrapbooks. Alabama events volume 3",
        "description": "Topics covered: Supreme Court upholds Civil Rights Commission hearings; Montgomery County ordered to release voting records; Mobile ordered to integrate municipal golf course; Macon County ordered to open voting registration to all; Bullock County voting registration declared unconstitutional; Jefferson County denies access to voter registration records; \"Freedom Riders\" violence in Birmingham and Montgomery. These scrapbooks, compiled by librarians at the Birmingham Public Library, contain newspaper clippings relating to the Civil Rights Movement. The clippings are arranged in three subject areas: national civil rights events, Alabama events, and Mississippi events. The clippings are arranged chronologically within the subject areas.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 16,
                "end": 29,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "supreme court",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9815000295639038,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 38,
                "end": 61,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "civil rights commission",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9879000186920166,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 72,
                "end": 89,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "montgomery county",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9316999912261963,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 125,
                "end": 131,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "mobile",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9726999998092651,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 176,
                "end": 188,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "macon county",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9359999895095825,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 233,
                "end": 247,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "bullock county",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9422000050544739,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 295,
                "end": 311,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "jefferson county",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9484000205993652,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 386,
                "end": 396,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "birmingham",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9790999889373779,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 401,
                "end": 411,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "montgomery",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9768999814987183,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 461,
                "end": 486,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "birmingham public library",
                "ner_confidence": 0.987500011920929,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 636,
                "end": 643,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9793999791145325,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 656,
                "end": 667,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "mississippi",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9797000288963318,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "7a9ecac842686eb3e60bdfb71f80d959",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement scrapbooks. National events volume 7",
        "description": "Topics covered: \"Reverse Freedom Riders\"; Albany, Georgia racial violence; school desegregation continues throughout the South; Albany Prayer Vigil; federal judge orders University of Mississippi to admit James H. Meredith. These scrapbooks, compiled by librarians at the Birmingham Public Library, contain newspaper clippings relating to the Civil Rights Movement. The clippings are arranged in three subject areas: national civil rights events, Alabama events, and Mississippi events. The clippings are arranged chronologically within the subject areas.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 42,
                "end": 48,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "albany",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9736999869346619,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 50,
                "end": 57,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "georgia",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9753999710083008,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 170,
                "end": 195,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "university of mississippi",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9804999828338623,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 205,
                "end": 223,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "james h. meredith",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9879000186920166,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 272,
                "end": 297,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "birmingham public library",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9886000156402588,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 447,
                "end": 454,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9803000092506409,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 467,
                "end": 478,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "mississippi",
                "ner_confidence": 0.979200005531311,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "fa86a046e733a85a01a4202928d75033",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "Civil Rights Movement scrapbooks. National events volume 12",
        "description": "Topics covered: arrival of Poor People's Mule Train in Washington, D, C; Supreme Court upholds 1866 civil rights law; \"Resurrection City\" leaders are jailed; violence in Washington, D. C. These scrapbooks, compiled by librarians at the Birmingham Public Library, contain newspaper clippings relating to the Civil Rights Movement. The clippings are arranged in three subject areas: national civil rights events, Alabama events, and Mississippi events. The clippings are arranged chronologically within the subject areas.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 73,
                "end": 86,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "supreme court",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9818999767303467,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 236,
                "end": 261,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "birmingham public library",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9886999726295471,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 411,
                "end": 418,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "alabama",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9787999987602234,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 431,
                "end": 442,
                "label": "GPE",
                "entity_span": "mississippi",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9782000184059143,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "c69393502c8f191a9af2d728e815dade",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "[Flyer: Black Music and the Civil Rights Movement]",
        "description": "Flyer advertising for the annual Junior Black Academy of Arts and Letters production of the Black Music and the Civil Rights Movement Concert Series. The event was held on January 17, 1993 at the Morton H. Meyerson Symphony Center, and the flyer outlines the rehearsal dates and featured performers. [1] p. ; 28 cm.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 33,
                "end": 73,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "junior black academy of arts and letters",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9886000156402588,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "ba96e948b0146ae9c454032ee59f7578",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "[Flyer: Black Music and the Civil Rights Movement]",
        "description": "Flyer for the annual Junior Black Academy of Arts and Letters performance and commemoration of the late Reverend Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. [1] p. ; 28 cm.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 21,
                "end": 61,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "junior black academy of arts and letters",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9890999794006348,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 117,
                "end": 140,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "martin luther king, jr",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9056000113487244,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "96b7e41fdf7bf5d5680b0d9bd175ff62",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "[Program: Black Music and the Civil Rights Movement]",
        "description": "Program for the annual Black Music and the Civil Rights Movements hosted by the Junior Black Academy of Arts and Letters on January 16, 2000 at the Morton H. Meyerson Symphony Center. [4] p. ; 28 cm.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 80,
                "end": 120,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "junior black academy of arts and letters",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9871000051498413,
                "wikidata_id": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "local_id": "5eef1f901094d4120a0e9260ce100e57",
        "cohort": "Cohort A (Racial/Ethnic Minorities)",
        "theme": "\"Civil Rights\" OR \"Civil Rights Movement\"",
        "title": "[Flyer: Black Music and The Civil Rights Movement]",
        "description": "Flyer advertising the annual Black Music and the Civil Rights Movement Concert hosted by the Junior Black Academy of Arts and Letters. The concert was developed by Curtis King and featured artist Eartha Kitt and conductor Rodena Preston. [1] p. ; 28 cm.",
        "entities": [
            {
                "start": 29,
                "end": 78,
                "label": "EVENT",
                "entity_span": "black music and the civil rights movement concert",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9020000100135803,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 93,
                "end": 133,
                "label": "ORG",
                "entity_span": "junior black academy of arts and letters",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9904000163078308,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 164,
                "end": 175,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "curtis king",
                "ner_confidence": 0.9897000193595886,
                "wikidata_id": null
            },
            {
                "start": 196,
                "end": 207,
                "label": "PERSON",
                "entity_span": "eartha kitt",
